Fahad Iqbal

Address: 14 Amblethorn Drive, Bolton, BL1 7BP

Email: <u>mfahdiqbal@hotmail.com</u>
Mobile: 07425 707505/07418 014124

Date of Birth: 13 June 1982

Qualification: BS Computer Science

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a highly experienced professional having diversified practical 17+ years extensive work experience in 3 large organizations in Pakistan and have the capability & great passion to work with enthusiasm, dedication and hard work. I am very proficient & possessing excellent professional skills including English Communication, Computer Networking, Office Administration, Business Development and Supply-Chain-Proposal-Management. I have great learning ability to accept new challenges within pressurized working environment. I am always willing to work overtime in order to achieve the assigned targets within tight deadlines being very cooperative, honest & active team-leader as well as team-member of a dynamic organization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

CURRENTAGE INTERNATIONAL MARKETING (PVT.) LTD., ISLAMABAD – PAKISTAN
 Jan 2008 – Oct 2019 (Manager MIS & Proposals)

Duties/Responsibilities:

- I joined the company as Assistant Manager MIS and soon got promoted to Manager MIS. My management observed my abilities to learn new things quickly, dedication to work, honesty, hard-work and hence promoted to Manager MIS & Proposals with additional duties of Business Development and Proposal Management.
- I was reporting directly to the CEO and staff members reporting to me with following duties but not limited to:
- First line and Second Line IT support (main point of contact for all employees) in a mixed environment of Microsoft Windows and MAC.
- Troubleshooting of day to day issues to the end users/employees.
- Working with Active Directory managing domain users and computer accounts, Group Policies, Offline Exchange Server, etc.
- Networking support and troubleshooting such as general fault finding using various utilities, mapping drives, shares etc.
- Printer maintenance, local and networked.
- PC and general hardware and software maintenance and support, including new builds and installs.
- Installation/re-installation of Windows.
- Creating backups and restoring data.
- Proactive and energetic approach to both personal assignments and Team collaboration
- Manage inventory and look after all local and foreign Procurement matters related to IT / office equipment.
- Ensure an orderly work environment and arrange maintenance / replacements of the office equipment.
- Advise all employees of Company Procedures, Policies & other matters.
- Administrative works e.g. printing of company stationary. Oversee record keeping, conduct interviews, train
 and supervise staff in Business Development/Admin department and manage company resources for optimal
 use including company vehicles, telephone, etc.
- Communicate with clients in energy sector (oil & gas, power, fertilizer) and with foreign vendors/principals to develop business and maintain conducive relationships.
- Source new foreign principals/suppliers for specific products and establish communication in order to perform evaluation and due diligence w.r.t. their technical & financial capabilities, etc.
- Prepare & review representation agreements with foreign principals/vendors.
- Introduce new principals and apply for Pre-qualification (PQ) of existing and new principals with the relevant clients and assist in preparation of Pre-qualification documents.
- Secure Tender Enquiries/RFQs/PQs from various clients, review and issue to appropriate bidders/principals.
- Assist principals in preparing bid documents and submit after detailed review & analysis.
- Arrange pre and post bid clarification responses to and from clients and principals.
- Support in contract negotiations with the clients and principals and assist in establishing payment terms, etc.

ADGROUP ADVERTISING & PUBLIC RELATIONS, ISLAMABAD – PAKISTAN

Apr 2007 – Jan 2008 (Assistant Network Administrator)

Duties/Responsibilities:

- Provide complete network and end user support to over 65 nodes.
- Implementation of a mixed environment of Microsoft windows and Apple Macintosh.
- Procurement of computer hardware.
- Assist in configuring HP ML 370 Servers with RAID as a Domain Controller, Exchange Server and Proxy Server, by using ISA 2004 and inter office chat software and network based online attendance system.
- Monitoring and maintenance of hardware equipment and manage inventory and data backup.

DAILY EXPRESS C/O PRINTEK (PRIVATE) LIMITED, ISLAMABAD – PAKISTAN Jun 2002 – Apr 2007 (Senior System Support Engineer)

Duties/Responsibilities:

- I joined the company in 2002 as Junior System Support Engineer and promoted to System Support Engineer and
 considering my performance I once again got promoted to the most senior position of Support Engineers i.e.
 Senior System Support Engineer.
- Set-up, Administration, Troubleshooting and Maintenance of LAN (100+ nodes) Islamabad office including installation of Servers, Network Printers, File server, softwares
- Administering Active Directory users, managing data backups and ensure 24x7 availability of resources
- Up-gradation of Windows NT servers to Windows 2000 servers.

SKILLS/ABILITIES:

- Detail-oriented thorough professional promoting expertise.
- Excel in a fast paced environment, Committed and self-motivated, strong communication skills.
- Strong work ethics, Business development, Powerful negotiator, Staff development.
- Proficient with computer applications, Target-oriented, Team leader and team player.
- Fully experienced professional able to handle more complex work or service provision
- Confident Procurement Specialist, knowledgeable in developing & managing client-vendor relations, tracking products and the methods needed to obtain the best pricing.
- Work without supervision to achieve agreed targets and goals
- Ability to handle entire procurement cycle and contribute towards growth of the organization.
- Maintain miscellaneous inventory records, Excellent at administration/logistics/management.
- Ability to negotiate, establish, and administer contracts.
- Comfortable working with clients from diverse backgrounds and cultural ethnicity
- Project management, researching and sourcing skills along with multitasking, prioritization & time management, able to process and understand data quickly.
- Analyze problems quickly and find immediate solutions to meet stringent time lines.
- General office administration, staff management.

ACHIEVEMENTS:

- Planned, developed and implemented complete computer network infrastructure in multiple branches/cities for Daily Express newspaper at my own
- Successfully implemented intranet chat system within office
- Maintained all systems and minimized the downtime for smooth operations

EDUCATION / CERTIFICATIONS:

- Degree: BS (Computer Science) 2003 2007 from International Islamic University, Islamabad, Pakistan
- Certification: Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP)
- Course: Microsoft Certified System Engineer (MCSE)
- Course: Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA)

REFERENCES:

Available on request.